<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Y11 Physics on</title><link>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/y11-physics/</link><description>Recent content in Y11 Physics on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/y11-physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Medical-Physics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Medical-Physics/</guid><description>Uses of Radioisotopes in Diagnostic Imaging: A gamma camera or SPECT camera (fig.1) is a camera that detects flashing light (scintillons) produced by gamma rays interacting with a sodium iodide (NaI) crystal at the front of the camera.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Nuclear-Physics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Nuclear-Physics/</guid><description>Decay When a radioisotope (A radioactive isotope (same element, different mass number (different neutrons))) undergoes radioactive decay, it will emit a high-energy particle or wave (radiation), there are several types of particles/waves emitted during radioactive decay: Alpha Particles - $\alpha$ $^4_2\alpha \rightarrow$ Same as a Helium nucleus Parent atom loses two protons and two neutrons during alpha decay Atomic number decreases by 2, mass number decreases by 4 Beta Particles - $\beta$ $^0_{-1}\beta \rightarrow$ Same as an electron Parent atom turns a neutron into a proton an electron, and an antineutrino, emitting the electron Atomic number increases by 1, mass number does not change $^0_{1}\beta \rightarrow$ Same as a positron Parent atom turns a proton into a neutron, positron and a neutrino (v)(v)(v) and the positron and neutrino are emitted Atomic number decreases by 1, mass number does not change Gamma particles - $\gamma$ $^0_{0}\gamma \rightarrow$ is an electromagnetic wave with a very high frequency and small wavelength Parent atom goes from an excited state to a base state Actual atom is unchanged Nuclear Equations Remember to balance it right or you&amp;rsquo;ll get it wrong.</description></item><item><title>Accuracy, Precision, and Error</title><link>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Accuracy-Precision-and-Error/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Accuracy-Precision-and-Error/</guid><description>Accuracy vs Precision Accuracy - Closeness to actual value (not possible, as measuring changes the system) Precision - Smallest unit of measurement of scale Experimental precision - Closeness of values to each other</description></item><item><title>Motion</title><link>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Motion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Motion/</guid><description>SUVAT Equations s - displacement (distance from origin) u - initial velocity (magnitiude + direction) v - final velocity (magnitude + direction) a - acceleration (change in velocity over time) t - time taken</description></item><item><title>Vectors</title><link>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Vectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Vectors/</guid><description>Vectors Vectors have magnitude and direction, scalars just have magnitude
Common vectors and scalars
Vector Symbol Unit Scalar Symbol Unit Displacement s m distance s m Velocity v m/s Speed v m/s Acceleration a $m/s^2$ temperature T ˚C\˚K Force F N Time t s Jerk j $m/s^3$ Work W J Vector Diagrams Demonstrate all similar vectors in the system Head-tail Resolved Either draw a compass or refer to the direction</description></item><item><title>Waves</title><link>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Waves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Waves/</guid><description>Types and Features of Waves There are 2 types of wave, longitudinal, and transverse.
Longitudinal waves are like sound, with the periodic compressions and decompressions of the medium through which the wave is travelling.</description></item><item><title>Y11 Physics</title><link>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Y11-Physics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jeffthedoggo.github.io/Binyan-Notes/Y11-Physics/Y11-Physics/</guid><description> [[Accuracy, Precision, and Error|Accuracy, Precision, and Error]] [[Motion|Motion]] [[Y11 Physics/Vectors|Vectors]] [[Waves|Waves]] [[Nuclear Physics|Nuclear Physics]]</description></item></channel></rss>